<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bala on Home</title>
    <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/authors/bala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bala on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.bala-krishnan.com/authors/bala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Tier-rifying oncall shift</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/tier-1-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/tier-1-outage/</guid>
      <description>Ah, on-call rotations. They keep you sharp, but sometimes they test your patience in the most unexpected ways. During an oncall shift with a previous employer, a seemingly minor configuration change cascaded into a major incident, taking down an entire production cluster. Here&amp;rsquo;s the story, along with the valuable takeaways that helped us prevent similar situations in the future.
The Plot Thickens: Tier 1 Networking and Missing Alerts
The incident stemmed from a change deployed to our Google Cloud Platform (GCP) cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Tracing</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/tracing/</guid>
      <description>Ever felt like your application operates in a black box? You know things are happening, but it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to pinpoint exactly where bottlenecks occur or why errors surface. This is where Distributed Tracing comes in, offering a powerful tool to illuminate the inner workings of your complex software systems.
Why is Tracing Essential? Link to heading Imagine a user journey through your application. They click a button, data flows across various services, and finally, a response appears on their screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Distributed Systems: A Journey Through Papers</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/exploring-distributed-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/exploring-distributed-systems/</guid>
      <description>As we step into a new year, many of us set personal goals to delve deeper into various domains of knowledge. For me, one such aspiration revolves around enhancing my comprehension of distributed systems. In this pursuit, I&amp;rsquo;ve curated a list of seminal papers spanning various facets of distributed systems, intending to dissect, analyze, and learn from them.
While there exists an abundance of resources on distributed systems—ranging from blog posts to podcasts and videos—I aim to contribute to this reservoir by documenting my journey through these papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fallacy of Command-Line Interview Questions: Why Problem Solving Should Trump Memorization</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/command-line-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/command-line-interviews/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-evolving landscape of job interviews, especially in the tech industry, there&amp;rsquo;s a trend that persists like an unwelcome guest at a party: the grueling interrogation of command-line knowledge. Picture this: you&amp;rsquo;re in a virtual interview, sweating bullets as the interviewer fires off questions about obscure commands or demands you regurgitate the contents of some long-forgotten system file. It&amp;rsquo;s the stuff of nightmares for many candidates, and frankly, it&amp;rsquo;s time we reassess its validity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPA! - An issue with resource allocation</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/opa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/opa/</guid>
      <description>In one of my previous roles at a leading cloud-based company, I encountered a fascinating challenge that underscored the importance of resource management in Kubernetes. While I can&amp;rsquo;t reveal specific company details, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a fictionalized account of an incident that carries valuable lessons for anyone navigating the complexities of scaling in a Kubernetes environment.
The Scenario Link to heading Picture this: a team is conducting a rigorous performance test, rapidly deploying numerous pods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Know Your Data: The Stats behind the Alerts</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/notes/stats-behind-alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/notes/stats-behind-alerts/</guid>
      <description>I came across this amazing video from Dave McAllister in the &amp;ldquo;WTF is SRE 2023&amp;rdquo; conference on the statistics behind the alerts.
Thanks to Dave for his clear explanation of the various concepts.
Here are my notes on the video:
Mean vs Median vs Mode - Mean = Measure of central tendency, the average value Median - In a sorted data set, median is the middle value Mode - Mode is the frequently used value in a dataset Arithmetic mean - Not the 50% mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical coincidences</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/historical-coincidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/historical-coincidence/</guid>
      <description>Two cities that I have lived and loved the most have been Chennai in India and Santa Barbara in the US. I was born in Chennai and brought up in its suburbs, Chennai was where I had my first job. Santa Barbara was the city I moved to from Chennai.
Image: Chennai Central Railway Station Image Courtesy: Jamal Haider
Image: Marina Beach, Chennai - the second longest beach in the world Image Courtesy: Wikipedia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SRE Interview Experience</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/sre-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/sre-interviews/</guid>
      <description>I resigned from my role at Salesforce in September of 2023 and have been interviewing with multiple companies for SRE/DevOps/Platform Engineering roles. I was offered an SRE role with Rad AI and I have accepted it and will be joining them in the last week of January. I am glad that I was finally able to get an offer and I am excited to be exploring site reliability for a medical AI product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google onsite interview - Systems SRE role</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/google-sre-onsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/google-sre-onsite/</guid>
      <description>I did a virtual onsite interview with Google for the Systems SRE role in 2022. This post is about my preparation for the interview and my actual interview experience.
In my previous post, I discussed the phone screen I had for the SRE role. After the phone screen, my recruiter got in touch with me, discussed the results of the interview and handed me over to another recruiter who handled the onsite interviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google tech screen - Systems SRE role</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/google-tech-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/google-tech-screen/</guid>
      <description>I had my phone screen with a member of the Google SRE team last week. As I mentioned in my previous post, I am interviewing with Google for the Systems SRE role. I was nervous about the interview, given that I had failed this round in my two previous attempts. The interview covers practical coding and scripting and Linux fundamentals/trivia. The best part about being considered for the systems SRE role is that you will not be asked complex algorithmic questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 days before a Google interview</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/google-sre-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/google-sre-interview/</guid>
      <description>I am interviewing for the Systems SRE role with Google (Alphabet) in about 2 days. The SRE team at Google is something that I have looked up to ever since I read the first SRE book. I have tried interviewing for the role twice previously and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to go past the phone screen both the times. Hoping that the third time will be the charm!
Google pioneered the concept of Site Reliability Engineering, which is an amalgamation of systems engineering, coding and scripting, and networking functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a year!</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/2021-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/2021-review/</guid>
      <description>I grew up in the southern part of India and one of the things I loved doing the most at the end of the year was reading through the year-end summaries that the newspaper &amp;ldquo;The Hindu&amp;rdquo; published. It was a summary of the important events for every day of the year with some articles written by the top newsmakers of the year. This blog post is my attempt to do the same about how I did during 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ever growing to-do list</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/2022-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/2022-to-do/</guid>
      <description>I set goals for how I want to grow my technical skills every year that I have been employed and fall short. 2021 was a similar year too. I set goals and fell short, by more than a mile.
So, what did I plan to learn this year? I wanted to get better with my Kubernetes knowledge and clear the CKA certification. How did I fare? I did learn a lot about Kubernetes as part of my job and my oncall duties, but I was not able to take the certification and had to cancel the registration for the exam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
