<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kubernetes on Home</title>
    <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kubernetes on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.bala-krishnan.com/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resizing StatefulSet PVs Without Downtime in Production</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/sts-resizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/sts-resizing/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I worked on resizing a statefulset. One of our workloads was constantly restarting due to the disk space filling up. The process of resizing the persistent volume of a statefulset is straightforward. You scale down the statefulset, modify the size of the underlying PVC, and then scale up the statefulset however, in this case, there were multiple complications and constraints. To begin with, our PVCs were configured to be deleted when they were not bound to any pod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the Certified Kubernetes Administrator Exam</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/cka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/cka/</guid>
      <description>One of the goals I set for myself for this year was to clear the Certified Kubernetes Administrator certification offered by CNCF. I have been working on Kubernetes since 2019. At Salesforce, I had the opportunity to work on managing more than 400 EKS clusters and control and data plane components in over 20 datacenters spread all over the world. I consider myself to be adept at troubleshooting issues with Kuberentes, but I wanted to get this certification in order to prove to myself that I understood the various concepts related to the operation of a Kuberentes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPA! - An issue with resource allocation</title>
      <link>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/opa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bala-krishnan.com/posts/opa/</guid>
      <description>In one of my previous roles at a leading cloud-based company, I encountered a fascinating challenge that underscored the importance of resource management in Kubernetes. While I can&amp;rsquo;t reveal specific company details, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a fictionalized account of an incident that carries valuable lessons for anyone navigating the complexities of scaling in a Kubernetes environment.
The Scenario Link to heading Picture this: a team is conducting a rigorous performance test, rapidly deploying numerous pods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
